Vikas Sharma

Senior Software Engineer

- ∨ks.sharmavikas96@gmail.com
- SRB-3A, Shipra Riviera, Indirapuram, Ghaziabad, India
- github.com/vikassharmag6

- 9582296350
- in linkedin.com/in/vikas-sharma-368297117
- stackoverflow.com/users/10453249/vikas-sharma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Altran

09/2020 - Present

Software Engineer

MothersonSumi Infotech & Design

07/2017 - 09/2020

PROJECTS

Samsung eStore

- A multilingual eCommerce react native app which uses keycloak for authentication and integrated microservices that follow a BFF design pattern
- Core functionality of app includes authentication with keycloak, product, cart, account functionality, and multilingual support.
- Used Redux toolkit, react-navigationV5, axios, keycloak, geolocation, localization, formik forms.

Factory Forms

- A hybrid app developed with react native which enables even non-programmers to effectively create wide range of mobile apps based on different business requirements.
- Successfully single-handedly implemented and received appreciation from client, worked cordially with server side and 2 deliverables made to the customer with no external defects.
- Core functionality of the app includes form generation and validation from JSON schema.

HRIS1 🗷

- HRIS1 app provides the most convenient way to mark office attendance by using facial biometrics and geofencing technology.
- This app also include contact tracing which uses BLE feature in android that shows people in close contact with someone who is infected with covid1g.

Enstructor

 An application developed for Vuzix M300 smart glass which enables hands-free process learning and guidance for workers in manufacturing plant. Made deliverables both for wearable glass and android application. [Android + Kotlin]

Connect1 3

 Connect1 is a mobile-based console that provides a platform to access application(s) being used in the Samvardhana Motherson Group (SMG). Implemented google recommended MVVM architecture component e.t.c. [Android + Java]

Enlightening Quotes 🗗

 A hybrid app developed with xamarin framework which provides daily new quotes using xamarin forms.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Technology (CSE) - 78%

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

<u>SKILLS</u>



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Seekho Learn in a minute. Remember forever

Seekho app developed with react native is India's first short learning app made for learners enabling them to learn almost anything in only a minute.

Let's Hear It 🗷

Implemented sound touch library in android using Android NDK and MVVM architecture.

It is an online business advertisement directory to facilitate the interaction among the business community.

File Tracking 🗗

An android application which tracks files in and out time from various department and know the current status for file.

LuckyWorld 🗹

Developed an android and iOS phishing app which collects user data and a Web App to show users message, call logs, device details and more.

TaskAssistent

A smart watch application used to assign a daily task from server.

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional Languages - Java, Kotlin, C#, JavaScript

Tools and Technologies - Android, React Native, Xamarin

Databases - Room, SQLite, Realm

IDE worked on - Android Studio, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Xcode, Unity

Repositories - GIT, Team Foundation Server

04/2013 - 03/2017

New Delhi